Guide to the Victorio A. Velasco Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Victorio A. Velasco papers
1920-1968
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1435
1435-003
Velasco, Victorio A., d. 1968
15.17 cubic feet (15 boxes)
Journalist, labor organization leader, civic leader, poet
After immigrating in the 1920s, Victorio Velasco became a participant and leader in many facets of Filipino-American life over the next half century. Velasco was perhaps best known as a leader of Seattle’s Filipino community. He published and edited the local Filipino Forum and served as the head of numerous Seattle Filipino community organizations. Because of his leadership in the Filipino community, many local and statewide organizations seeking to improve race relations sought him out to serve on their boards and committees. In addition to his leadership among Seattle’s Filipinos, Velasco also participated in the Filipino American labor movement. Like many other Filipinos during his time, Velasco spent most of his summers working in Alaska canneries and participated in the cannery unions’ turbulent internal politics.
Velasco was born in Asingan, Pangasinan, The Philippines, ca. 1903. After graduating from high school he taught in Manila and worked as a reporter for the Manila Times before emigrating to the U.S. in 1924. There he attended five colleges in Washington State before earning his B.A., M.A., and fulfilling some of the requirements for a Ph.D. at the University of Washington. Velasco had begun writing poetry in high school and early on was successful at finding publishers for his work. By the time of his death Velasco’s poetry had appeared in eleven anthologies and various newspapers and magazines.
After coming to the U.S., Velasco spent his summers working in the canneries alongside other Filipinos, who had begun filling most cannery positions after the loss of Japanese immigrants in the 1920s. Cannery work was known for being particularly strenuous and the employers often tried to take advantage of their Asian immigrant laborers, but the Filipinos developed a strong union to engage in collective bargaining with the employers. The Seattle branch of the Cannery Workers’ and Farm Laborers’ Union was organized in 1933 and represented Filipino-American cannery workers. However, the Filipino workers became frustrated with the AFL because of its stand on racial issues and in 1937 affiliated themselves with the CIO’s United Cannery, Agricultural, Packinghouse and Allied Workers of America, Local 7.
With union representation, the cannery workers were able to win concessions and improve wages and working conditions, but Local 7’s internal politics were often bitter. Many of the union elections featured personal insults and redbaiting. Velasco was involved in many of the elections both as a candidate and as a supporter of others running for office, but until the late 1940s, his attempts at winning a union office were unsuccessful. Velasco also was involved in a major split in Local 7 during the immediate postwar period. Many Local 7 members accused officers of corruption, which led to an investigation by its international union, which suspended or expelled three of Local 7’s top officers. These ousted officers formed a rival organization, the Seafood Workers’ Union (SFWU) and conducted a membership drive to try to displace Local 7. Although Velasco was not implicated in the Local 7 investigation, he joined the SFWU and became its secretary. There are a number of possibilities for why he might have joined.
One factor might have been the persistent regionalism within the Filipino-American community. Many of the people who joined the SFWU were from Velasco’s region of the Philippines. Ideology and politics may also have been a factor in Velasco’s decision, as members of the SFWU used anti-Communist rhetoric to attack Local 7. Velasco’s politics were consistently conservative and he saw Communism as a grave threat.
After merging with the AFL Alaska Fish Cannery Workers’ Union, the SFWU was able to enter a NLRB election that would allow cannery workers to determine which union would represent them. Redbaiting became a weapon in the campaign against Local 7, which affiliated with the International Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen’s Union (ILWU). In 1950 the ILWU finally won collective bargaining rights and subsequently became Local 37 of the ILWU. Velasco then joined Local 37 and remained a member for the rest of his life, serving frequently as a delegate and as secretary-treasurer.
Newspaper publishing was also a large component of Velasco’s life. In the early 1920s Velasco worked as editor for the Philippine Seattle Colonist and as the Seattle correspondent for the Philippine Republic. In 1928 he became the founder, editor, and publisher of the Filipino Forum, which served as a newspaper for the Seattle Filipino community. In 1937 Velasco had to suspend publication, but resumed printing the Forum after the outbreak of World War II. During the interim he published or wrote for various other Filipino newspapers, including the Seattle Filipino Outlook, Northwest Forum, Philippine Review, and the Philippine Advocate.
Throughout his life in Seattle Velasco was heavily involved in local civic organizations, mostly within the Filipino community. In 1928 he was part of a group of UW Filipino students who founded the Seattle Filipino Clubhouse Fund. The Fund was intended to raise enough money to build a center for Filipino students at the university, but the plans never materialized. However, Velasco later changed the organization’s name to Filipino Community of Seattle, Inc., and set out to build a center for the entire Seattle Filipino community. Decades later, in 1965, the center was finally completed and was open for social events and recreation. Velasco also was a founder, president, and board member of the UW Filipino Alumni Association after World War II and founded both the Pangasinan Association of the Pacific Northwest and the Asinganian Club, which were comprised of people who came from his region of the Philippines.
Velasco also served other civic organizations that were not targeted specifically at Filipinos. Many of these groups were trying to reach out to the city’s and state’s diverse groups to try to improve race relations. He helped found the Jackson Street Community Council in 1946 and served as its first secretary and then as a board member. Other community organizations that Velasco served include the King County Advisory Council of the Washington State Board Against Discrimination, and the Board of Trustees of the Neighborhood House, which served inner-city youth.
Velasco died in Waterfall Alaska in 1968. He had been working at a cannery there when the bunkhouse caught on fire. After escaping safely, Velasco went back to retrieve his typewriter but was unable to escape a second time.
Correspondence, a diary, speeches and writings, ephemera, programs, newsletters, newspapers, minutes, reports, and personal papers and records from Velasco’s civic and labor organizations. The accession is divided into personal papers and subgroups based on the organizations that Velasco served.
The Filipino Forum subgroup consists mainly of materials intended for publication in the newspaper: news releases, speeches, photographs, and letters to the editor. This subgroup also includes records of the Philippine Advocate and other publications that Velasco edited or contributed to, including the Philippine Seattle Colonist (1927), and the Velasco News Service.
Campaign materials from local union elections are in subgroups throughout the accession. Much of the literature is polemical and appears to come from candidates whom Velasco supported, as well as from Velasco himself.
Personal Papers consist of materials that could not be subgrouped. Included are Velasco’s poems, letters to family and friends, schoolwork, date books, and other materials. The remainder of the Personal Papers consists of publications that he collected, speeches and writings, newspapers and ephemera from Filipino community organizations.
Major correspondents include New England Fish Company, Philippines Consulate, and Alaska Salmon Industry.
Some of the newspapers in this accession are available on microfilm in the Microform and Newspaper Collection. Microfilm A4137 has the Filipino Forum and A5612 has other Filipino-American newspapers from Washington State.
View selections from this collection in digital format.
Open to all users.
The bulk of the papers came from Velasco’s wife, Josefina, in 1970 and 1972. Rufino F. Cacabelos donated a small addition in 1977.
The visual materials that form part of this collection are described and indexed in
A Guide to the
.
Inventory/container list available in Special Collections.
The Cannery Workers and Farm Laborers’ Union, Local No. 7 (Acc. 3927) also contains files that Velasco kept while he was an officer.
The Pinoy Archives in Seattle also contains records related to Seattle Filipino American history and the cannery workers.
Velasco, Victorio A., d. 1968$vArchives;;; Dominguez, Maria Louisa
Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Jackson Street Community Council (Seattle, Wash.); Seafood Workers' Union; Cannery Workers' and Farm Laborers' Union. Local 77 (Seattle, Wash.); Alaska Fish Cannery Workers' Union of the Pacific (SIU-AFL); International Longshoremen's And Warehousemen's Union. Local 37 (Seattle, Wash.); Civic Unity Committee (Seattle, Wash.); Seattle (Wash.). Council of Social Agencies; Council On Aging For Seattle And King County; University of Washington. Filipino Alumni Association; Filipino-American Intercommunity Council of the Pacific Northwest; Neighborhood House (Seattle, Wash.); Pangasinan Association of the Pacific Northwest; Washington State Board Against Discrimination; Philippine Commonwealth Council Of Seattle; Filipino Nacionalista Party in America; Avon House Publishers; Filipino Students Christian Movement In America; Alaska Salmon Industry, Inc.; Caballeros De Dimas-Alang (Fraternity); Filipino and American Community of Puget Sound; Filipino Youth Activities of Seattle
Philippines$xPolitics and government
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Immigrant, ethnic, and racial groups; Labor
Filipino Forum; Japanese Exclusion League journal
- Personal Papers
  - Biographical Features, 1937-68 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Organizational Features - Various Organizations, 1939-65 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Incoming Letters
    - Abella, Sebastian, 1932 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Acosta, Leonarda, 1925-37 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Aldaba, Dalisay, 1951-59 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Aquino, Marco A., 1930-36 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Aquino, Sixta V., 1922-25 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Arroyo, Simeon Doria, 1931-39 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Avon House Publishers, 1937-41 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Baylon, Tel I., 1938-48 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Bryant, Alice Franklin, 1951-66 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Filipino Students Christian Movement in America - Manuel Adeva, 1932-36 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Garrott, Jane (“Mother”), 1926-27 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Lincoln, Annie, 1927-29 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Lincoln, E.H. (“Mother”), 1927-29 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Marsh, Ruth, 1925-26 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Martinez, Mercedes, 1951 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Mattmueller, Eleanor, 1926-29 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Micu, Bernardo, 1937-38 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Milanio, M.P., 1931-32 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Panelle, Michael Anthony, 1933-34 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - parades, Quintin (Resident Commissioner of the Phlippines), 1936 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Pagkalinawan, E.A. (“Carnation”), 1957-59 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Pelly, Thomas M., 1958-59 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Philippines (Government), 1922-58 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Querubin, Josefina, 1923-60 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Rueca, Lolita, 1949-50 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Sevidal, Benigno S., 1928-38 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Velasco, Auring, 1940-51 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Velasco, Gregorio B., 1928-59 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Velasco Leonor, 1936-51 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Wechel, Edith Van, 1929-30 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - A-Z, 1925-67 (Box-folder 1/33-52)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1927-67 (Box-folder 1/53-55)
  - General Correspondence - Delphine Brooks, 1930-37 (Box-folder 1/56-58)
  - Minutes - Various Organizations, 1928-62 (Box-folder 1/59)
  - Subject Series
    - Legionarios Del Trabajo, 1945-65 (Box-folder 1/60)
    - Maria Louisa Dominguez
      - General Correspondence, 1950-65 (Box-folder 2/1-10)
      - Divorce Records, 1953-55 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Libel Suit, 1956 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - United Good Neighbors, 1952-59 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1942-66 (Box-folder 2/14,15)
  - Address Books, 1942-56 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Account Books, 1928, 65 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Diaries, 1924-55 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Reports, 1940-65 (Box-folder 2/19-24, 3/1-2)
  - Speeches And Writings
    - V.A. Velasco, 1920-67 (Box-folder 3/3-9)
    - Philippine President, 1935-53 (Box-folder 3/10,11)
    - Redadtrini, Ildefonso - “Skid Road Philosopher”, undated (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Rojo, Trinidad, undated (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Others, 1935-64 (Box-folder 3/14-20)
  - Newsletters
    - Bataan, 1953-62 (Box-folder 3/21-23)
    - The Chomly Spectator (cannery newsletter), 1927 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Filipino Student/Bulletin, 1932-41 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - The Informer, Pullman, WA, 1929 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Larawan, 1956-63 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Moral Re-Armament, 1959-62 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Mother’s Bulletin (International House, UW), 1926 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Northern Light - Washington Committee For Protection of Foreign Born, 1957-58 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Nu’s Letter - Phi Delta Kappa, 1945-66 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - The Philippine Newsletter, 1956-61 (Box-folder 3/32,33)
    - Philippine Seattle Colonist, 1927 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Philippine Weekly Economic Review, 1959-67 (Box-folder 3/34-35,4/1-4)
    - Philippines Panorama, 1957-58 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Prism, 1946-47 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Racial Equality Bulletin, 1951-64 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - The Sea Gull News (Alaska), 1928 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Seattle Pacific College Bulletin / Alumni Magazine, 1948-65 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Seattle Filipino Outlook - University of Washington, 1930 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Varsity Filipino Weekly, 1926 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-64 (Box-folder 4/12-21)
  - Newspapers
    - Filipino American from Washington State OVERSIZED, 1928-55 (Box-folder 14)
    - Filipino American from Other States OVERSIZED, 1928-55 (Box-folder 13)
  - Programs And Announcements
    - Caballeros De Dimas-Alang, 1928-66 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Churches, 1928-66 (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Concerts and Plays, 1942-59 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Filipino and American Community of Puget Sound, 1941-63 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Filipino Columbians, 1954-62 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Filipino Events, 1931-65 (Box-folder 4/27,28)
    - Filipino Events, Out of State, 1939-65 (Box-folder 4/29,30)
    - Filipino Lodges, 1949-66 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Rizal Days, 1920-64 (Box-folder 5/2-5)
    - Miscellaneous (Non-Filipino), 1932-65 (Box-folder 5/6-9)
  - Ephemera
    - Cards (Identification and Business), undated (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Filipino Related, 1946-60 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Filipino Youth Activities of Seattle, 1959-63 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Literary, undated (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Philippine Tourist Brochures, undated (Box-folder 5/14,15)
    - Political, 1948-60 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - University of Washington, 1936-59 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 5/18,19)
  - Invitations, 1930-64 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Pamphlets, 1910-64 (Box-folder 5/21-27,6/1-5)
  - Financial Records, 1965 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Conferences And Conventions, 1958-62 (Box-folder 6/7,8)
  - Court Papers, 1953-58 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Resolutions, 1954-60 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Legislation, 1930-59 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Lists, 1954-62 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Yearbook - The Shocsonian, 1921 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Clippings, 1930-61 (Box-folder 6/14,15)
  - Miscellany, 1935-63 (Box-folder 6/16-19)
  - Questionnaires - Filipinos In America Today, undated (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Certificates, 1948-70 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Schoolwork, 1935-48 (Box-folder 12)
- Cannery Workers’ And Farm Laborers’ Union. Local #7
  - Organization, 1940 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Incoming Letters, 1938-48 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1940-48 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Intra-organizational Correspondence, 1935-48 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Minutes, 1946 (Box-folder 6/26)
  - Contracts - Alaska Salmon Industry, Inc., 1947-48 (Box-folder 6/27)
  - Speeches And Writings, 1947 (Box-folder 6/28)
  - Clippings, 1938 (Box-folder 6/29)
  - Membership, 1940-41 (Box-folder 6/30)
  - Ephemera, 1946 (Box-folder 6/31)
  - Newsletter- “local 7 News”, 1945-49 (Box-folder 6/32)
- Seafood Workers’ Union
  - Incoming Letters
    - Alaska Salmon Industry, Inc., 1948 (Box-folder 6/33)
    - A-Z, 1947-48 (Box-folder 3/34-36)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1947-48 (Box-folder 6/37,38)
  - Minutes, 1947-48 (Box-folder 6/39)
  - Financial Records, 1948 (Box-folder 6/40)
  - Membership, 1947-49 (Box-folder 6/41,42)
  - Memoranda, undated (Box-folder 6/43)
  - Requisitions, 1948 (Box-folder 6/44)
  - Newsletter- “the Truth”, 1947 (Box-folder 6/45)
- Alaska Fish Cannery Workers’ Union Of The Pacific (SIU-AFL)
  - Organization, undated (Box-folder 6/46)
  - General Correspondence, 1949-52 (Box-folder 6/47)
  - Minutes, 1949 (Box-folder 6/48)
  - Ephemera, 1949 (Box-folder 6/49)
- Longshoremen’s And Warehousemen’s Union, International. Local #37
  - Organization, 1951 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Incoming Letters, 1953-68 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1953-59 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Intra-organizational Correspondence, 1951-60 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - General Correspondence, 1953-58 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Minutes, 1949-52 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Financial Records, 1951-59 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Negotiations, 1948-68 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Contracts - Alaska Salmon Industry, Inc., 1951-59 (Box-folder 7/9,10)
  - Reports, 1953-59 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Crew List, 1959 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Speeches And Writings, undated (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Ephemera, 1940-57 (Box-folder 7/15-17)
  - Subject Series - Biennial Convention
    - Minutes, 1953, 57 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Resolutions, 1953 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Reports/Rules, 1953 (Box-folder 7/20)
- Civic Unity Committee
  - Organization, 1964 (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Incoming Letters, 1958-63 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1950-64 (Box-folder 7/23-26)
  - Minutes, 1953-64 (Box-folder 7/27-29)
  - Reports, 1955-63 (Box-folder 7/30-34)
  - Newsletters - Fair Play, 1958-59 (Box-folder 7/35)
  - Financial Records, 1958-60 (Box-folder 7/36)
  - Ephemera, 1947-59 (Box-folder 7/37)
- Council Of Social Agencies, 1947-58 (Box-folder 7/38)
- Council On Aging For Seattle And King County, 1957-68 (Box-folder 7/39)
- Filipino Alumni Association (UW), 1947-67 (Box-folder 7/40)
- Filipino Community Of Seattle
  - Historical Features, 1939-66 (Box-folder 7/41)
  - Constitution And Bylaws, 1939-52 (Box-folder 7/42)
  - Incoming Letters, 1933-66 (Box-folder 7/43)
    - Philippine Consulate, 1945-65 (Box-folder 7/44)
    - Philippine Government Embassy, 1933-66 (Box-folder 7/45-48)
    - Miscellaneous A-Z, 1944-66 (Box-folder 7/49)
  - Outgoing Letters (Box-folder 7/49)
  - Minutes, 1956-63 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Speeches And Writings
    - Velasco, Victorio, 1941 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Angeles, Mariano B., 1958 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Philippine Counsul, 1952-60 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Rojo, Trinidad, undated (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Misc., 1946-58 (Box-folder 8/6,7)
  - Financial Records, 1941-59 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Lists, 1956 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Newsletters, 1959 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Reports, 1958-62 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Clippings, 1948-61 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Miscellany, 1949-65 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Elections, 1947-64 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Ephemera, 1948-66 (Box-folder 8/15-17)
  - Newsletters- “queen Contest Courier”, 1946 (Box-folder 8/18)
- Filipino Forum
  - Historical Features, 1946 (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Incoming Letters, 1928-65
    - Angeles, Mariano B., 1936-59 (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Aquino, Marco A., 1929-38 (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Christian Friends For Racial Equality, 1939 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Dionisio, Johnny R., 1950-51 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Malasarte, Blas D. and Jean. O., 1962-67 (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Philippine Government, 1943-64 (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Rustia, Manuel S., 1926-28 (Box-folder 8/26)
    - Yap, Diosdado M., 1935-57 (Box-folder 8/27)
    - A-Y, 1928-65 (Box-folder 8/28-38)
    - Unidentified, 1929-66 (Box-folder 8/39)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1928-67 (Box-folder 8/40-45)
  - Legislation, 1944-63 (Box-folder 8/46)
  - Financial Records, 1944-59 (Box-folder 8/47,48)
  - Ledger, 1946-48 (Box-folder 8)
  - Lists, 1948-59 (Box-folder 9/1,2)
  - News Releases
    - Anti-Tuberculosis League of King County, 1958-63 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Columbo Conference, Seattle, 1958 (Box-folder 9/4-6)
    - Jackson Street Community Council, 1949-66 (Box-folder 977)
    - Philippine Commonwealth, 1944 (Box-folder 9/8-10)
    - Philippine Consulates, 1948-64 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Philippine Government, 1942-63 (Box-folder 9/12-14)
    - Philippine Embassy, 1958-64 (Box-folder 9/15,16)
    - Philippine Resident Commissioner to the United States, 1945-46 (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Seattle World’s Fair, 1962 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-65 (Box-folder 9/19-25)
  - Newsletters
    - Philippine Affairs, 1948-58 (Box-folder 9/26)
    - Philippine News, 1948-53 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Philippine News Briefs, 1948-53 (Box-folder 9/28,29)
    - Phillipine News Digest, 1945-49 (Box-folder 9/30)
    - Philippines Consulates, 1927-58 (Box-folder 9/31)
    - Phillipine Government, 1943-58 (Box-folder 9/32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1927-58 (Box-folder 9/33)
  - Newspapers - Filipino Forum Oversized, 1943-69 (Box-folder 15)
  - Speeches And Writings
    - V.A. Velasco, 1926-65 (Box-folder 9/34)
    - Auburn News, undated (Box-folder 9/35)
    - Bremerton News, 1929-30 (Box-folder 9/36)
    - Yap, Diosdado M., 1936-44 (Box-folder 9/37)
    - Others, 1930-66 (Box-folder 10/1-9)
  - Notes, 1957-59 (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Subject Series - Queen Contest, 1954 (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Reports - Columbo Plan, 1957 (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Clippings, 1925-67 (Box-folder 10/13-19)
  - Miscellany, 1958 (Box-folder 10/20)
  - Ephemera, 1934-65 (Box-folder 10/21,22)
- Filipino Inter-Community Council Of The Pacific Northwest, 1953-59 (Box-folder 10/23)
- Filipino Nacionalista Party In America, 1949-52 (Box-folder 10/24)
- Jackson Street Community Council
  - Organization, 1945-59 (Box-folder 10/25)
  - Incoming Letters, 1943-61 (Box-folder 10/26)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1946-64 (Box-folder 10/27-32)
  - Minutes, 1946-65 (Box-folder 10/33,11/1-13)
  - News Releases, 1952-62 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Financial Records, 1947-64 (Box-folder 11/15-17)
  - Membership Lists, 1946-60 (Box-folder 11/18)
  - Legislation, 1956-58 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - Speeches And Writings, 1955-60 (Box-folder 11/20,21)
  - Newsletters - Jackson Street Community Newsletter, 1956-64 (Box-folder 11/22,23)
  - Reports, 1947-61 (Box-folder 11/24-26)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 11/27)
  - Miscellany, 1947-61 (Box-folder 11/28)
  - Ephemera, 1951-64 (Box-folder 11/29)
- Neighborhood House, 1950-61 (Box-folder 11/30-33)
- Pangasinan Association 0f The Pacific Northwest. (Asinganian Club), 1939-68 (Box-folder 11/34)
- Philippine Commonwealth Council Of Seattle, 1935-36 (Box-folder 11/35)
- Washington State Board Against Discrimination, 1957-64 (Box-folder 11/36-39)